Sean Yan Jhia Choo

Contact Information

Address : UK

E-mail : choo.sean72@gmail.com

Mission Case Study, Jupiter Orbit Explorer

Introduction

I am a 3rd year MEng student with practical experience in engineering projects, alongside a passion in programming and design. I am meticulous in my work and have an inherent curiosity to explore new opportunities. I aim to apply my skills into diverse aerospace projects that can challenge my abilities, while enabling me to showcase my strengths and creativity in solving problems.

Education Background

Education Background	
MEng (Hons) Aeronautics & Astronautics Engineering (2:1) University of Southampton, Southampton, UK	Oct 2021 – Present
Cambridge General Certificate of Education Advanced Level (3A* & 1A) Taylor's College, Subang Jaya, Selangor	Jan 2020 – Jun 2021
Cambridge International General Certification of Secondary Education (6A*, 3A & 1B) Taylor's International Puchong, Puchong, Selangor	Dec 2017 – Nov 2019
Work Experiences	
UX Developer Internship, Ambrrr (www.ambrrr.com) - Worked in a startup environment creating a responsive website based given designs using html, CSS & JavaScript, along with multiple frameworks & APIs.	Oct 2022 – Sep 2023
 University Research Internship, University of Southampton Malaysia Successfully investigated each countries' ability to produce biodiesel from the availability of raw materials using Excel & Power Pivot, with over 10 million cells. 	Jun 2022 – Sep 2022
Coding Team Member, Quizona Chemistry V2.0 - Collaborated with the UI/UX team to implement the redesigned UI using Swift & Xcode. Achieving top 100 in the App Store's education category.	Jan 2022 – Jan 2022
Engineering Experiences	
Individual Project, Vibroacoustic analysis of thermal fatigued CFRP Investigated the use of vibroacoustic methods and FE simulations, when analysing the health of CFRP used in hydrogen fuel tanks for a hydrogen fuelled future.	Oct 2023 – Present
Programming Lead, Unmanned Aerial Vehicle (UAV) Design Project - Wrote and managed the Arduino circuit & code to ensure a seamless integration between the gimbal and data logger, along with the other electronics.	Feb 2023 – Jun 2023
Arduino Coder, Dino Design Project Wrote the complete code using Arduino code to enable multiple different movements and functions of the dinosaur with an emphasis on abstraction.	Nov 2022 – Jan 2023

Analysed the communication window based on orbital behaviours of the planets and spacecraft using Python, to determine the power requirements for the s/c.

Oct 2022 - Dec 2022

Product Design Lead, James Dyson Award 2022 - Tekkai

Apr 2022 - Jul 2022

- Led a group of students to design a self-retracting electrical plug using SolidWorks and created the concept animation using Blender for the submission.

Awarded for achieving 3A* and 1A in Cambridge A Levels May June

Awards & Achievements

Southampton Malaysia Aviator's Society (Best New Club/Society Award) - Awarded by University of Southampton Malaysia Student Association for being a new society with the most student engagement.	May 2023
Pecipta'22 International Conference by Institutions of Higher Learning (Gold Award) - Awarded for the innovation of a mobile app, Quizona Chemistry, that can assist in the learning of chemistry subject for multiple syllabuses.	Nov 2022
POSC 2022 Infographic Competition (Finalist) Successfully created an infographic about the oil palm industry and its contribution towards UN SDGs, which went on to become a finalist.	Aug 2022
Defense, Security, Sustainality Competition (Gold Award & 1st Place in Category) - Awarded by UPNM for a mobile application that improves Malaysian Education.	Aug 2022
 MyIPO (Intellectual Property Corporation of Malaysia) Certificates Curated an instruction manual for an educational app, Quizona Chemistry, and the manual for a DIY Dual-Fermometer Hygrometer using Adobe Illustrator. Ref number: LY2022J02865, LY2022J02866 	Jul 2022
Quizona Chemistry, Sijil Penghargaan Atas Komitmen Dalam Pembinaan Aplikasi	Mar 2022
Taylor's Top Achiever Award, Taylor's College	Oct 2021

Other Experiences

Secretary, Southampton Malaysia Aviator's Society (SMAS) - Coordinated meetings and worked with 5 other committee members to curate marketing materials for club events and aviation industry related outings.	Sep 2022 – May 2023
 Group Member, 2022 SDG Summer Camp – Net Zero Carbon Fuels Explored ways to achieve the SDGs set by the UN and assisted in the group presentation about the viability of ammonia as fuel for coal powerplants. 	Jun 2022 – Jul 2022
Group Member, 'Green for Life' 2022 LCC International Summer School - Explored the sustainability potential of renewable fuels and participated in a group presentation discussing the options to achieve carbon neutrality in Asia.	Jun 2022 – Jul 2022
Member, Southampton University Space Flight Society (Malaysia)	Oct 2021 – Jun 2023

Skills

CAD & Simulation	SolidWorks (intermediate), COMSOL (intermediate), Ansys (intermediate)
Programming	Python, Arduino, Simulink (beginners), html, CSS, JavaScript, Git
Linguistic Abilities	English (fluent), Mandarin (2 nd language)

Interests